MICHAEL DIEDRICKS

Software Developer

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a graduate developer with a background in architecture, I decided to make the career switch to dev so I could leverage the scalability of software to solve problems.

My unique background has exposed me to the challenges of working in large teams while maintaining documentation standards to meeting deadlines. My experience often had me using my technical knowledge of our design software to solve design problems in varying situations.

I'm interested in a role where I can build tools for people to work together and smarter.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- · React, HTML & CSS, Ruby on Rails, jQuery
 - Coordinating document standards, assisting juniors/onboarders,
 - · VS Code, Heroku, Firebase, Github
- I enjoy 3D printing crafts, the outdoors and building things for myself

GET IN TOUCH

0403 848 240 michael.diedricks@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mdiedricks github.com/mdiedricks

PROJECTS

CoWandr Web - in production

CoWandr, 2020

- · Co-owned travel planning project with business partner
- Building browser-based prototype of travel app in React
- · Database design and back-end of MVP with Firebase

General Assembly Projects

Questlog - Game Tracker

- · Database design and built back-end with Firebase
- · Built front-end with React
- · User-auth and deployment via Firebase

Dessert Delivery App

- · Database design and built back-end with Rails
- · Co-built front-end in React
- · Coordinated UI design with design-focused teammate

CAREER

BIM Assistant & Graduate Architect

Hayball Architects, 2017 - present

- Help develop digital library and maintain BIM infrastructure
- · Assist Sydney office with CAD problems and software issues
- · Ran/coordinated training sessions to upskill Revit users
- · Building documentation and

Woods Bagot

Draftsman, 2016 - 17

- Built scheduling tables for tracking items on large construction projects
- · Large team building documentation for large-scale projects

Girvan Waugh

Draftsman, 2015 - 16

- Guided new members of the team through our documentation processes
- · Helped develop documentation standard for growing office
- · Independent design and documentation for small workplace projects

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly, 2020

Masters of Architecture

University of Sydney, 2018

Bachelor of Design in Architecture

University of Sydney, 2014